

JAVIER MORALES

IT SYSTEMS ENGINEER

CONTACT

+34633433201

MORALESJMORENO@GMAIL.COM
LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JAVIERMORALESM/

PROFILE

Inventive and solutions-driven IT professional with over 12 years of experience in information security, compliance, risk management, and vulnerability assessment. Specialities include DBs, Virtualization, Storage, Networking, Cybersec and vast exposure to support multi-platform international environments.

EXPERIENCE

CYBER SECURITY ENGINEER

THE WORKSHOP. (SPAIN) | APR 2022 - PRESENT

- Implementing and managing security systems across the entire organisation's network, including next-generation firewalls (NGFW) intrusion detection/prevention systems (IDS/IPS), web application firewalls, endpoint security solutions, etc.
- System maintenance, troubleshooting and BAU activities for network and endpoint security solutions (SIEM, Network and Application Firewalls, End point Detection Response, Vulnerabilities patching, Access Control & IAM, Cisco Security Suit).

PLATORM LINUX ENGINEER

THE WORKSHOP. (SPAIN) | MAY 2021 - MARCH 2022

- Administering the organization server infrastructure in a multi-location environment based on Linux/Windows systems running under OpenStack / VMware
- Continuous Integration and Deployment SCM tools (Git, Bitbucket), DNS Automated deployment and maintenance
- Automatization Platform management tools, such as Puppet and Ansible (AWX) to build fast automated deployment processes (laaC)

SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR & CLOUD ENGINEER ESENTIRE LTD. (IRELAND) | NOV 2018 - APRIL 2021

- Creating and utilizing tools to monitor our applications and services in the cloud including system health indicators, trend identification, and anomaly detection (NOC)
- Planning, designing and developing cloud-based applications and services (IaaS, PaaS, SaaS)
- Developed experience with Cloud-based hosting solutions (AWS-EC2/S3, VMware, VRops)
- Provide High-Level system management solutions

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER LEVEL 2 / 3

VMWARE (IRELAND) | SEP 2016 - NOV 2018

- Manage and support vSphere & Vrops incidents, multiplatform technical assistance, Network L2/L3 and Storage troubleshooting
- Proactively provide guidance following best practices

IT SYSTEMS & OPS ENGINEER

HAVAS MEDIA (SPAIN) | MAY 2015 - AUG 2016

- Managing cloud environments in accordance with company security guidelines.
- VMware Administrator (P2V Migration deploy, configure and manage virtual infrastructure)
- Hands-on experience on Amazon Web Services AWS (S3, EC2, VPC, CloudWatch)

VMWARE ENGINEER

WINCOR NIXDORF (SPAIN) | MAY 2014 - MAY 2015

- Stealthily plan and lead the deployment of the cloud solution
- VMware SME Subject Matter expert
- Designing and implementing new Virtual Environments (server-less integrated VMware)



JAVIER MORALES

IT SYSTEMS ENGINEER

2ND LINE IT ENGINEER

ROCHE PHARMACEUTICAL (SPAIN) | NOV 2013 - MAY 2014

- Strategize daily monitoring, management, troubleshooting and issue resolution to systems and services hosted on cloud resources
- Supporting VMware, Networking, and Backup management, Storage Systems, Blade Servers, SAN, Backup infrastructure

HELPDESK LEVEL 1-2 IT ENGINEER

VODAFONE (SPAIN) | DEC 2010 - NOV 2013

- Advance application & hardware support for internal company employees
- Using ticketing tools such as Spider, Remedy and HP Service Manager

EDUCATION

MASTER DIPLOMA IN CYBER SECURITY (MSC LEVEL 9) UNIVERSIDAD DE LA RIOJA UNIR, SPAIN 2020-2021

HIGHER DIPLOMA WITH HONORS IN CLOUD COMPUTER SCIENCE

NATIONAL COLLEGE OF IRELAND, IRELAND | 2017-2019

TECHNICAL HIGHER DIPLOMA IN MULTIPLATFORM APPS **DEVELOPMENT**

I.E.S. I.E.S EL RINCÓN, SPAIN | 2011-2013

TECHNICAL HIGHER DIPLOMA IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS

I.E.S. POLITÉCNICO, SPAIN | 2003-2005

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

SPANISH, ENGLISH

SKILLS

- Software Define DataCenter Veeam Backup & Disaster SDDC
- Linux, DBs, Networking
- Amazon AWS (IAM, EC2, S3, CloudWatch, VPC)
- Technical Documentation, **POCs**
- CI/CD Secure Software Dev Life Cycle (SDDLC)
- Security Compliance, ISO 27001. SIEM and SCCM tools

- Recovery
- VMware Design, Deployment & Implementation
- Monitoring (Nagios, Icinga Solarwinds, Service Now)
- Migration Projects (On-Premise to Cloud & Microservices)
- Python & Bash Automation scripting

CERTIFICATIONS

- VCP550 VCP5-DCV
- DOUBLE VCP VCP6-DCV & VCP6-NV (2V0-621D - 2V0-642 NSX)
- 3V0-623 VCAP 6 DCV DEPLOYMENT
- PMP BY IPMA

- COMPTIA LINUX+
- LPIC-1: SYSTEM **ADMININSTRATOR**
- AWS SOLUTION ARCHITECT ASSOCIATED
- INTERNAL AUDITOR ISO 27001:2013 BY TÜV RHEINLAND